Won eht tepmurt snommus su niaga -- ton sa a llac ot raeb smra, hguoht smra ew deen -- ton sa a llac ot elttab, hguoht delttabme ew era -- tub a llac ot raeb eht nedrub fo a gnol thgiliwt elggurts, raey ni dna raey tuo, "gniciojer ni epoh; tneitap ni noitalubirt," a elggurts tsniaga eht nommoc seimene fo :nam ynnaryt, ytrevop, esaesid, dna raw flesti. 

Nac ew egrof tsniaga eseht seimene a dnarg dna labolg ecnailla, Htron dna Htuos, Tsae dna Tsew, taht nac erussa a erom luftiurf efil rof lla dniknam? Lliw uoy nioj ni taht cirotsih troffe? 

Ni eht gnol yrotsih fo eht dlrow, ylno a wef snoitareneg evah neeb detnarg eht elor fo gnidnefed modeerf ni sti ruoh fo mumixam regnad. I od ton knirhs morf siht ytilibisnopser -- I emoclew ti. I od ton eveileb taht yna fo su dluow egnahcxe secalp htiw yna rehto elpoep ro yna rehto noitareneg. Eht ygrene, eht htiaf, eht noitoved hcihw ew gnirb ot siht rovaedne lliw thgil ruo yrtnuoc dna lla ohw evres ti. Dna eht wolg morf taht erif nac ylurt thgil eht dlrow. 

Dna os, ym wollef Snacirema, ksa ton tahw ruoy yrtnuoc nac od rof uoy; ksa tahw uoy nac od rof ruoy yrtnuoc. 

Ym wollef snezitic fo eht dlrow, ksa ton tahw Acirema lliw od rof uoy, tub tahw rehtegot ew nac od rof eht modeerf fo nam. 

Yllanif, rehtehw uoy era snezitic fo Acirema ro snezitic fo eht dlrow, ksa fo su ereh eht emas hgih sdradnats fo htgnerts dna ecifircas hcihw ew ksa fo uoy. Htiw a doog ecneicsnoc ruo ylno erus drawer, htiw yrotsih eht lanif egduj fo ruo sdeed, tel su og htrof ot dael eht dnal ew evol, gniksa Sih gnisselb dna Sih pleh, tub gniwonk taht ereh no htrae s'doG krow tsum ylurt eb ruo nwo. 

Nhoj F. Ydennek, Yraunaj 1691 
